<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>

<!-- Put site-specific property overrides in this file. -->

<configuration>




<property>
  <name>http.agent.name</name>
  <value>Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/47.0.2526.73 Safari/537.36</value>
  <description>HTTP 'User-Agent' request header. MUST NOT be empty - 
  please set this to a single word uniquely related to your organization.

  NOTE: You should also check other related properties:

    http.robots.agents
    http.agent.description
    http.agent.url
    http.agent.email
    http.agent.version

  and set their values appropriately.

  </description>
</property>


<property>
	<name>fetcher.parse</name>
	<value>true</value>
	<description>If true, fetcher will parse content. Default is false, which means
	that a separate parsing step is required after fetching is finished.</description>
</property>



<property>
  <name>fetcher.threads.per.queue</name>
  <value>100</value>
  <description>This number is the maximum number of threads that
    should be allowed to access a queue at one time. Setting it to 
    a value > 1 will cause the Crawl-Delay value from robots.txt to
    be ignored and the value of fetcher.server.min.delay to be used
    as a delay between successive requests to the same server instead 
    of fetcher.server.delay.
   </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.content.limit</name>
  <value>-1</value>
  <description>The length limit for downloaded content using the http://
  protocol, in bytes. If this value is nonnegative (>=0), content longer
  than it will be truncated; otherwise, no truncation at all. Do not
  confuse this setting with the file.content.limit setting.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.server.delay</name>
  <value>0</value>
  <description>The number of seconds the fetcher will delay between 
   successive requests to the same server. Note that this might get
   overriden by a Crawl-Delay from a robots.txt and is used ONLY if 
   fetcher.threads.per.queue is set to 1.
   </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>plugin.includes</name>
  <value>protocol-http|urlfilter-regex|webcollector-nutch|index-(basic|anchor)|indexer-solr|scoring-opic|urlnormalizer-(pass|regex|basic)</value>
  <description>Regular expression naming plugin directory names to
  include.  Any plugin not matching this expression is excluded.
  In any case you need at least include the nutch-extensionpoints plugin. By
  default Nutch includes crawling just HTML and plain text via HTTP,
  and basic indexing and search plugins. In order to use HTTPS please enable 
  protocol-httpclient, but be aware of possible intermittent problems with the 
  underlying commons-httpclient library.
  </description>
</property>



</configuration>
